nationalrail.co.uk 2019-12-25

# National Rail Enquiries - Privacy Notice

The purpose of this notice is to make you aware of how we will manage and protect your personal data. You can use the short cut links below to go directly to specific sections.

## Who we are

Train Information Services Limited (TISL) manages the National Rail Enquiries (NRE) website on behalf of [Britain’s train companies](https://www.nationalrail.co.uk/tocs_maps/tocs/TrainOperators.aspx). TISL is the data controller and, as such, is responsible for ensuring the lawful and appropriate handling of all the personal data that you provide to National Rail Enquiries.  
National Rail Enquiries is a trade mark of TISL.  TISL also trades under the name Rail Delivery Group.  
To contact us regarding our use of your data, please [click here](https://app-eu.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/ad1e1d5b-4c16-4f89-bb91-f590011deb67). Alternatively, you can write to us at TISL,200 Aldersgate Street, London EC1A 4HD.

## Our lawful basis for collecting your data

We collect personal data from you when you create an online account with the NRE, so that you can use our services. Collecting your data is necessary for us to provide these services to you.  
We will treat your data in an appropriate and lawful manner, in accordance with data protection laws.

## What data we collect

If you use this site to search for journeys without using an account, we do not keep any of your information.

If you register for an account then we request your name and optionally some contact information.  
If you also choose to add journey alerts, specific journeys and/or stations to your account, we will save the information you provide so you do not have to repeat it.

We use cookies across our website to improve your experience and our website’s performance. To find out more about cookies, read our [Cookie Policy](https://www.nationalrail.co.uk/191702.aspx).

Cookie Settings

## Sharing information with other data processors

Any information you provide will only be used by NRE, train operating companies and by our suppliers: AWS (website hosting), IMImobile (digital provider for iPad app and SMS alerting), KCOM (support our website hosting and mobile apps), Eckoh, (automated phone service), Indicia (who provide out customer database), Salesforce (who send our marketing emails), Vodafone (who send out txt messages), Teleperformance (who provide customer support) and Thales (digital services provider).  
If you participate in a survey with us your survey responses will be processed by our survey supplier (Survey Monkey).  
We will not share your details with any other third parties for marketing purposes unless you provide us with your consent. If you consent to marketing, you can find out more about the communications you’ll receive in our Marketing & Contact Policy.

## Keeping your data safe

We protect your privacy by ensuring we have the appropriate security measures in place. We ensure that our suppliers process your data in an appropriate, lawful and safe manner.  
If you participate in a survey with us your data will be held with our supplier (Survey Monkey) in the United States under an EU approved data protection framework. It will be anonymised for reporting purposes and then deleted after 30 days.

## What we do with your data

The data we collect is used to maintain your NRE account and provide you with the optional services you have requested. We will also use your details to advise of any changes to our terms and conditions and/or privacy notice.

We do some analysis on our customer data for sales analysis and marketing research, including demographic, geographic and attitude analysis to understand who our customers are in groups rather than as individuals.

## How long do we keep your data?

Your account will be active while you keep using it. If you have not logged into your account for two years we will delete your account and any associated information.  
If you set up an account but do not validate it using the email we send you, the data you have entered will be held for 30 days. After that time, it will be deleted.

## Your rights

You have several rights to data protection which are set out below. To contact us in relation to your rights regarding how we use your data, please [click here to submit a request](https://app-eu.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/ad1e1d5b-4c16-4f89-bb91-f590011deb67).

## Subject access request

You have the right to request that we give you a copy of the data we hold about you. This is called a ‘Data Subject Access Request’.

## Deletion of personal information

You have the right to request that we delete any data that we hold on you.

## Object to processing of personal information

You have the right to object to the processing of your information for specific purposes such as direct marketing.

## Restrict processing of personal information

You have the right to request that we restrict processing of your information if you believe the information that we hold is incorrect, or you can show that our processing is unlawful, or you would like us to stop processing your data but do not want us to erase it. 

## Right to rectification

If your details are incorrect, incomplete or have changed, you can change these at any time by logging in to [your account](https://ojp.nationalrail.co.uk/personal/login/secure).

Alternatively, please [click here](https://app-eu.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/ad1e1d5b-4c16-4f89-bb91-f590011deb67) and complete our online form to request changes to the data that we hold on you.

## How to contact us

To exercise any of your rights set out above, please [click here](https://app-eu.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/ad1e1d5b-4c16-4f89-bb91-f590011deb67) and complete our online form or contact us using the details provided below:

Data Protection Lead for NRE  
ATOC Ltd, 200 Aldersgate Street, London EC1 4HD.

Tel: 0207 841 8000.

Please include your name and email address, so that we can deal with your request.

## Complaints

You have the right to complain about our processing to the Information Commissioner if you believe we are not processing your data in a proper manner - see <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/handling/> for more information.

## National Rail Enquires Contact Centre & Train Tracker™ service

National Rail Enquiries Contact Centre and Train Tracker™ service:  All calls are recorded for the purposes of quality assurance; we also store your telephone number in Train Tracker to identify your previous journey details, which speeds up the process and enhances your overall customer experience. We will not share your details with any other third parties.

If you do not wish your telephone number to be stored, you can block your number by using the prefix of ‘141’ (mobile and landline) before dialling us. Alternatively, you can contact your provider to withhold your number on all your calls.  
Last updated 30 April 2019.
